<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-30T21:40:32+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ollyj.uk</title><subtitle>Thoughts &amp; Pears</subtitle><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><entry><title type="html">Article 13 Is Concerning</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/27/article-13-is-concerning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Article 13 Is Concerning" /><published>2019-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/27/article-13-is-concerning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/27/article-13-is-concerning.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the European Copyright Directive had been approved. The legislation holds numerous components (or “Articles”) for member states to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particular component that has caused the most uproar is called “Article 13”.  And there are questions being asked about the future of online video-sharing platforms as a result. The particular clause will require large video-sharing platforms, like YouTube, to put measures in place that ensure liability is covered for works uploaded by users that infringe copyright holders; and, if liability is not covered, that said works are not made available on the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what measures do YouTube need to put in place to achieve this? The site already has as system, amongst others, called ContentID that automatically detects infringing material and takes action depending on the right holders’ demands. But even ContentID and YouTube’s other copyright handling systems aren’t entirely accurate and have been open to abuse by those looking to silence or bully content creators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There’s multiple examples of this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/9eN0CIyF2ok&quot;&gt;Matt Hoss vs. H3H3&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/jzXSQ5f08sA&quot;&gt;IHateEverything vs. Derek Savage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise that Universal, Warner, and James Blunt (who sat in front of the camera reading a script) have all come out supporting the particular article. After all, Content ID pays horribly. But I am worried about what it’ll mean for the future of the site. YouTube &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; the future of entertainment. Some channels are pulling in millions of views &lt;strong&gt;daily&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;weekly&lt;/strong&gt;, far surpassing the viewership of some popular TV channels and shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Musicians have massively benefitted from the site too. Monstercat was born on YouTube in 2011 and now it is arguably the biggest electronic music label in the world; shedding light on incredibly talented bedroom producers. This is just one example out of many.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s lots of hysteria surrounding the news and many people don’t seem to know what will happen when these laws come into effect. But I personally believe musicians should take another look and ask themselves if this new directive will really benefit them in the long run; especially if sites like YouTube will need to seriously hinder their platform as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can read the full directive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.europarl.europa.eu/sides/getDoc.do?pubRef=-//EP//NONSGML+TA+P8-TA-2018-0337+0+DOC+PDF+V0//EN&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly</name></author><category term="comment" /><summary type="html">Yesterday the European Copyright Directive had been approved. The legislation holds numerous components (or “Articles”) for member states to achieve.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SF-UR</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/sfur.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SF-UR" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/sfur</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/sfur.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grove Street. Home. At least it was before I fucked everything up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An alternative radio station with a selection of underground House and Disco tracks from the 80s up to present day.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><summary type="html">Grove Street. Home. At least it was before I fucked everything up.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">v i c e c i t y</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/vicecity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="v i c e  c i t y" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/vicecity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/vicecity.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;get down saturday night&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A collection of Funk, Soul, and Disco from the 80s and 90s.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><summary type="html">get down saturday night</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BRUCH</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/23/mgmt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BRUCH" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/23/mgmt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/23/mgmt.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;artist-bio&quot;&gt;Artist Bio&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can find BRUCH on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/bruchmusic/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/35ht3cw9emBnkLoQXpKEvj?si=N9_bZszvTs-8WSaWYpcxIg&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Described by her followers as having elements of Björk, Kate Bush, Suzanne Vega, and Goldfrapp, all wrapped into a tiny, artistic explosion, BRUCH is a purveyor of curious, electronic sounds, multi-layered vocals and ethereal melodies, bringing her classical cello training into the mix for an eclectic juxtaposition. BRUCH is completely self-produced, and 98% of the sounds you hear in her music are created entirely by her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BRUCH’s music is like nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She takes influence from artists such as Massive Attack, Alice Phoebe Lou and David Bowie, along with a wide array of classical composers. A proud ‘owner’ of her Asperger’s Syndrome, BRUCH has been creating music since the age of thirteen. Her music is unique and diverse, spanning the genres of folk, pop and electronica, with a Nordic twist thrown in for good measure. But in quiet moments, she can be found listening to anything from Satie to Sondheim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her last three singles, Empty Land, Welcome, and CROWN. were snapped up by BBC Introducing for their Saturday night show, to great acclaim from both the host, Stephanie Nieuwenhuys, and the show’s audience, and she performed a two-song Live Lounge and interview for them in August. You can watch on iPlayer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p06l8qqm&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the live tracks, Tortoise Skin, was from her recently released EP, Autis, which takes listeners on a multi-faceted journey through her autistic creativity. During the five-song EP, the audience journeys from ambient, hypnotic moments into bass-driven, thunderous tribal drumming, all accentuated by her multi-layered cello sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2019 will see BRUCH appearing on the BBC Introducing Stage at Winchestival, plus sets at Hastings Fat Tuesday and the Metropolis Blue Label showcase launch night, with many more to be announced…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><summary type="html">Artist Bio</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">acid://</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/acid.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="acid://" /><published>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/acid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/playlists/2019/03/23/acid.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Music, for me, is like love. Sometimes you can’t describe it, you just feel it … so when I listened to acid music I was like: ‘Fuuuuuck’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;- Peggy Gou&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><summary type="html">Music, for me, is like love. Sometimes you can’t describe it, you just feel it … so when I listened to acid music I was like: ‘Fuuuuuck’</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Metropolis Blue</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/16/metblue.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metropolis Blue" /><published>2019-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/16/metblue</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/entries/2019/03/16/metblue.html">&lt;p&gt;Metropolis Blue is a joint venture by Metropolis Studios and ACM. The label is run by - and dedicated to - students of the university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My role in the label is currently Marketing and Videography. As part of the Videography role I am in charge of the team that are dedicated to producing high quality content. This includes live events, interviews and acoustic sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 11th of March 2019 we released a short showreel of our first live event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//HBZvnWIs9AA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Olly Wiggins</name></author><summary type="html">Metropolis Blue is a joint venture by Metropolis Studios and ACM. The label is run by - and dedicated to - students of the university.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Metropolis Blue: Showreel</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/16/metblue-showreel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Metropolis Blue: Showreel" /><published>2019-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/16/metblue-showreel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/03/16/metblue-showreel.html">&lt;p&gt;After a successful launch party for the student-run Metropolis Blue record label I created this short montage to show off some of the best moments from the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to the team, Joe Dallison and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/kB.mediaservices/&quot;&gt;Kailan Blanks&lt;/a&gt; for helping film the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Side note: Can you spot the footage that was shot on an iPhone? Follow up post coming soon.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed//HBZvnWIs9AA&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Olly</name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html">After a successful launch party for the student-run Metropolis Blue record label I created this short montage to show off some of the best moments from the night.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">BRUCH: Artist Takeover playlist</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/02/25/bruch-spotify-playlist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BRUCH: Artist Takeover playlist" /><published>2019-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/02/25/bruch-spotify-playlist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2019/02/25/bruch-spotify-playlist.html">&lt;p&gt;An artist I am currently managing, BRUCH, has published an “influences” playlist. There’s some great stuff on here and I recommend checking it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/a7cqk8pi4bcc2aoikko3fbpnf/playlist/2aAiAmOLYo4jcg0ptdP9AK?si=87tsILAjR6m2w_F0NFsiTg&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to visit the playlist.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Olly</name></author><category term="post" /><summary type="html">An artist I am currently managing, BRUCH, has published an “influences” playlist. There’s some great stuff on here and I recommend checking it out!</summary></entry></feed>